

Ndifreke Okorie

+358-468955815 Andi7@yahoo.co.uk https://github/packetech

in Ndifreke Okorie

Proactive self-taught software developer with a passion for problem analytics and solving. Specializes in full-stack development, solution architecture, project management, JavaScript, Python and other web tech stack. Recognised for leadership abilities, teamwork and project delivery.

Professional Experience

Bouygues Construction

Apr 2013 - June 2021

IT Manager Abuja, NG

IT Infrastructure Management and Project Leadership (Nigeria)

- Deployed and decommissioned IT infrastructure across 4 new construction project sites, while simultaneously managing IT operations for 6 existing sites using IT staff and outsourced contractors to meet operational timelines
- Directed the successful relocation of the head office IT data center to a new location, with all it's legacy connectivities and firewalls

Cotecna Dec 2008 - Mar 2013

Assistant IT Manager Abuja, NG

IT Infrastructure manager (Northern Nigeria)

Setup the VSAT ground station, backend application servers (including Windows/Linux, MS Exchange, DNS, DHCP, AD, WSUS, Firewall, Routers) and the network of the company's valuation and classification center (VCC) in Abuja using HP G4 servers and Cisco devices for smooth trade facilitations.

Projects

Fruit Shop

https://ndibuilt-full-stack-ecommerce.netlify.app

- Developed a full stack ecommerce fruit shop app using NextJS and TailwindCSS for an effective online sales and UX
- Integrated Zustand for global state management of the app components
- Incorporated Stripe billing via API and Key Secret for users payment and backend transaction management

Hulknormous (Fitness App)

https://ndibuilt-fitness.netlify.app

- Designed an intelligent workout web app using ReactJS and TailwindCSS for personalized body training plans
- Creating a rule-based algorithm for smart workouts taking care of all experience levels and difficulties

Todo App

https://ndibuilt-todo.netlify.app

- Built a responsive todo app using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to enable users maintain a list of important todos
- Used device browser local storage to persist entries, so CRUD activities can be effectively carried out

Al Chatbot

https://github.com/packetech/Coding Journey/tree/main/THE-COMPLETE-JAVASCRIPT-COURSE/Projects/AI chatbot

- Created a command line AI chatbot using JavaScript, to act as a quick and simple knowledge base enabling users ask for any information and get appropriate answers
- Incorporated Eden AI apiKey authentication to use Eden API
- Included an async function to take care of network delays

Education

Arcada University of Applied Sciences

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

Master of Engineering, Big Data Analytics

Helsinki, Fl

Demonstrated expertise in software development and resampling techniques

Nasarawa State University

Nov 2020 - pending

Master of Science in Computer Sciences (Software Engineering Concentration)

Keffi, NG

• Demonstrated expertise in data structure and algorithm best practices

University of Texas

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

PG program, AI and Machine Learning

Austin TX, USA

• Demonstrated expertise in deep learning, computer vision and NLP

University of Calabar

Oct 1990 - Jun 1995

B.Sc. (hons) in Physics

Calabar, NG

Demonstrated expertise in astrophysics, geophysics and computer programming

Skills

JavaScript ReactJS, NextJS, SvelteKit, Qwik, Node.js, Express.js

Python Data analytics, visual analytics, Al & ML, Django, Flask

Web HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Firebase, GIT, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP

Database NoSQL, SQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo.db

Design Canva, Figma, Storyboard, PixIr, Photoshop, Coreldraw (for UI/UX, wireframe, etc.)